=-SF字幕同好会-=
本字幕仅供学习交流，严禁用于商业途径
片名：《暂告安全》
翻译&校对：gcthor@HDC hkwwcl@HDC
转载请保留信息，欢迎有志之士加入，请在HDC致信hkwwcl
布鲁克林，纽约，一小时前
把她带过来！轻点，她只是个孩子！
好吧，我大可以杀了她
南京，中国，一年前
204,35倍，是另外一种算法，加起来是350
如果用另外一种算法，加起来是365
只有一个算法是对的
（两人都做错了，定义域是X|X≠-2，
嘴上说的和黑板上的也牛头不对马嘴）
苏先生，我没有不尊重你的意思
但是你的算法是错的
梅
我们要把你转去另一个学校
可是我的朋友都在这儿，而且我的妈妈...
梅，你太聪明了，你是个天才
你该上一个特殊的学校
你可以找新朋友的
别难过，梅，我们永远都是你的朋友，听说北京的小孩人都很好的
你在那儿会过得很开心的
我根本就不喜欢数学
我喜欢我现在的朋友，我不想要交新的朋友，我不喜欢数学
你来做数学，我们给你写信，
我们每个星期都给你往北京写封信
你发誓？
当然，你想让我们失去一个有名的朋友吗？
不，梅，我们永远都是你的...
新泽西联航中心球馆
这是我的侄女，白玉
认识吧？
她在我朋友的班里
她说啊，你的脑筋啊很像电脑
我跟你的老师讲过了，他也这样说
你知道了吧
很可爱啊
电脑很讨厌，太容易留下痕迹，他们还说...
走开呀，走开！
你学的东西你不会忘的，是不是？
那我到你的家，把你的妈妈杀掉好不好啊！
很好，很好
看来他们说的对了
苏先生告诉我你小的时候你爸爸已经走掉了
你的妈妈现在很病了
很快你变成一个人，你喜欢孤独吗？
放心，我们会好好照顾你的妈妈
张，你的新爸爸
他呢会带你漂洋过海，不过那边那里的人呢很喜欢
找我们的麻烦，所以我要你
帮我们算一算
卫路的店，这个礼拜是两万六千，上个礼拜是二十六
侯进每个礼拜是正好一万五千
他在博易街的店
五月份在丢钱，但是七月八月份他就赚回来了
中国城，纽约，一年后
邵成，上个礼拜是42，这个礼拜是42.5
每个月盈利增长7%
莫特区整个盈利总共上升了72535
我们从梁先生那里拿了5%
他们都每个礼拜盈利6千到8千
上个礼拜是八十万，这个礼拜也是八十万
停！
不要打了，拜托，不要打了
今晚，你们会有一个新的场上工头
如果钱又少了，那就不知道谁会走！
今天晚上他请
肯定不是我请
肯定你啊，这么多钱
他赢了这么多钱
看来你还是不懂这个生意，不说了
吃你的饭吧
梅，到你房间去记住这些数字
我已经记住了
这些数字很重要
为了你妈，你要认真一点，知道吗？
你真的记住了？
我可以给你重复一遍，但是又长又无聊
你看，还没到一年呢，她已经自信的很了
如果，她说她可以背出密码，她就能背出
我保证
好了好了
我们要交给你一个很重要的工作
梅，这是你的指令
张会带你见一个人，那个人会给你一个新的数字
记住那个数字
然后呢张会带你去一个地方，你会得到最后的指令
你学的很快
如果干的好，你会跟着韩叔前途无量
梅，我跟他们讲他们想知道的事情
他们给了我一把一把的钱
没事，你要是这么做他们也会帮助你的
你真是个笨女人
你不知道生意
你给了他们想要的东西，现在他们要杀了你
什姆亚金和其他人消失了是什么意思？
有人把她带走了
不是警察，他还差点干掉几个警察
也不是中国人，我不知道他到底是谁
干掉他，活捉女孩，不行就全干掉
我能查到的就是这些了
怎么样?
我们现在在找一个男的，他和一个女孩在一起
他有武器，非常危险，警察局的人说他是…
谁杀了那个俄国人?
我不知道,他没有告诉我
他有没有问到那个数字？
每个人都问那个数字
那你跟他们讲些什么呢？
我什么都没说
什么？
你在撒谎！！！
韩叔叔我当然不会给你撒谎的
打个电话告诉他们把阿梅的妈妈干掉
因为她的女儿是骗子
韩叔叔，我发誓，我假装不会说英文也听不懂
他们又吼又叫的但是我什么都没说，因为我知道你会生气的
我向我妈发誓
我从来不知这种时候该说什么
什么时候？
在我杀人之前
我们被袭击了
他们不是俄国人，好像是警察
不过他们比警察更厉害
派点人来，他们杀了很多人，快点啊，我们需要...
告诉张，尽快拿到那个数字然后把跑腿的干掉
这个数字由我们自己来破解
你们听懂了吗？
最尊敬的叔叔
这里有两千九百九十五万美元
我们会还余下的5万，再加10%的利息
如果万一您还生气
我必须告诉您，我知道您在中国城生意的每一个帐号
还有汇钱到中国的途径
您不找我们的麻烦，我们也不会找您的麻烦
来追我们的话，你的世界就完了
我保证说话算话
给我准备飞机票
我再也不想看到这个
鬼地方！
=-全片完，谢谢观赏-=
更多精彩影视，尽在HDCHINA.ORG
警察跟我们干上了
是吗？
你没有办法？
你这个不动脑筋的笨蛋,如果你让警察
或俄国人先找到那个女孩,我就砍了你人头
我们开打吧
她一定在这里，不过我看不清楚
干扰太多
等一下
等一下！
我找到她了
谁？
你以为是谁？我是皮特,你电话里没我号码吗？
皮特？警察说在地铁里发现你跟...
警方报告有误
其他人被...
什么声音？
抱歉，信号不好
我拿到数字了
什么？
在她被劫走前，我们从她那拿到数字了
我跟条子玩了几个小时的捉迷藏
伊哥，把数字记到手机里
说吧，告诉我数字
你疯了吗？数字在一公里外一张纸上，你在哪？
他可能带警察来了
我们要清场吗？
如果有警察，我们最好避开人群
而且需要有利地形
好的，皮特...
现在给你个机会做英雄
曼梦西卡见
快来
我马上到
你在骗我
You're lying to me.
没有！我不知道你在说什么
I'm not.
I don't know what you're talking about.
我不知道你想要什么，我发誓
I don't know what you want from me.
I swear I don't.
我有三个孩子
I have three children.
作为父亲，首先要学会的
The first thing you have to learn
as a father is to know
就是知道你的孩子何时在欺骗你
when your children are lying to you.
你在欺骗我，如果你不说真话
You're lying to me,
and if you don't stop,
我就要用你们那些有名的手段
I'm going to use one of those tortures
your people are so famous for
来折磨你弱小的身体，直到你告诉我一切
on your little body
until you tell me what I want to know.
最后一次，告诉我那些数字
For the last time,
give me the numbers.
梅！
Mei!
你怎么还敢来这？
How dare you come here!
You have no right!
- 妈妈！别打了！住手！
- 你没资格待在这里！没资格！
- Ma, enough! Stop!
- You've no right to be here. No right!
你应该被关在监狱里！监狱里！
You should be in jail!
滚出去！你给我滚出去！
You get out of here!
You get out of here.
- 对不起
- 我要杀掉你！我会杀掉你的！
- I'm sorry.
- I'll kill you! I'll kill you!
你个废物！那孩子不应该出现在擂台上！
Piece of garbage. The kid
should never been in there with me.
路克，别这样！你疯了吗？
Luke, come on. What, are you crazy, man?
- 走开！
- 给我走开！
- Get off.
- Get off, now!
我从来都不喜欢你，路克
I never liked you, Luke.
你比擂台上90%的人都厉害
You're a betterfighter than 90%
of the guys you go in the cage with,
但你却任人蹂躏
but you just let 'em pound on you
like you're a side of beef.
你几乎输给过擂台上的每一个笨蛋
You already lost to every chump
in the circuit.
但是昨晚
But last night, of all nights,
你应该在第二轮输掉的，你个混蛋
you're supposed to go down
in the second, you son of a bitch.
- 仅仅一拳！
- 退后！
- Once.
- Back off.
我就打了他一拳！你从哪里找到他的，操场？
I hit him once. Where'd you find him,
the fucking playground?
Youtube，你个混蛋
YouTube, you asshole.
在你把他打晕前，那个孩子还是个网络红人
The kid's an internet sensation
until you put him in a coma,
坦白说，我并不关心这个
which frankly
I do not give a shit about.
但是你让我输掉了100万美元
But you cost me a million dollars,
当然这和你让德切斯基输掉的比起来就不算什么了
which is nothing
compared what you cost Docheski.
很好！这个名字耳熟吧？
Yeah. You recognise the name?
他在你身上下了大赌注
He was betting on you big time
to take the dive.
他会把这一切都怪罪到我头上来的
And he's gonna take it out on me too
因为他知道这件事情是我这白痴搞出来的
'cause he knows I'm the schmuck
that set this whole thing up.
除非我把你的脑袋送给他
Unless I deliver your head
with a down payment.
你知道俄国人是什么样子的
You know how the Russians are.
梅
Mei.
你打对号码了，有什么事就留言吧
You got the right number,
so leave the right message.
听到后立刻给我回电，安妮，立刻
Call me when you get this, Annie.
I mean right away.
如果你出去了，别回家
If you're out, don't go home.
我不是在吓唬你，记得赶紧回电话
If I'm scaring you, that's good.
Call me.
安妮？
Annie?
就这样？
That's it?
我听说你是个硬汉啊
I heard you were
some kind of a tough guy.
不挣扎下？
No fighting?
就直接跪在地上像只求死的狗一样？
You're just going to sit on the floor
like a dog who wants to die?
不好意思搞得那么乱
Sorry it had to be so messy.
这些家伙还在学习中
The boy is still learning.
我虽然不是医生，但我想她有孩子了
And I'm not a doctor,
but I think she was eating for two.
我们就像查尔斯・曼森家一样
We're like Charlie Manson family, no?
我父亲本想派其他人来的，但我想锻炼下
My father was going to send
someone else, but I'm making my bones.
你就靠杀害那些没有还手能力的人来锻炼
You make your bones by killing someone
who can hurt you back.
那会是谁呢？你？
And who would that be? You?
好吧，当然是你
Well, why not?
你刚杀了你老婆
You just killed your wife.
我没杀她，是你杀的！
I didn't kill her. You did.
但是，你想伤害我？很好
Look, you want to hurt me? Good.
我倒想看看你能做些什么
I want to see you try.
杀了我吧
Get it over with.
杀了你？你让我父亲输钱，让我的家族难堪
Over? You cost my father money,
made my family look bad.
现在我们想把你作为一个特例对待
Now we're going to make
an extra special example out of you.
我们查过你的档案，没有什么有趣的东西
So, we looked into your records.
Not much to find.
为城市的卫生系统工作
Work for city,
garbage collection, sanitation.
收益不错，但是缺乏魅力，不是么？
Good benefits but no glamour, eh?
父母双亡，没有兄弟姐妹
Father and mother dead,
no brothers or sisters,
这真是糟糕
which is too bad,
我本想把他们都干掉的
because I would like
to take them from you too.
但是你爱你的老婆，我们知道这点
But you love your wife.
We know that.
那么，这样子说定了：
So here's the deal.
你可以走了，不过我们会盯着你的
You're free to go,
but we will have eyes on you.
不是一直，但是我们会在你最不希望出现的时候出现
Not always, but when
you least expect it, we'll be there.
任何一个你想结交的人，甚至是交谈过的
Anyone you try to make friends with
or even talk to,
反正是有过任何交集的人
other than ordering a hot dog
or something,
都会像你老婆一样因你而死
will die, like your wife,
because of you.
当然你可以随时结束这一切！跳桥
Of course, you can always end it,
jump off a bridge,
卧轨
throw yourself in front of a train,
将你的不朽的灵魂送去地狱，如果你相信这些狗屁
damn your eternal soul to hell,
if you believe in that kind of bullshit.
就我个人来说，我不相信
Personally, I don't.
所以，如果我是你，我宁愿去自杀
So I'd go for it if I were you.
但是我不是你
But I am not you.
感谢上帝
Thank God.
所以做你想做的事吧
So do what you want.
如果你明天还在这，我们会杀掉房东
If you're still here tomorrow,
we're going to kill the landlady.
- 她叫什么名字？
- 特巴洛斯基
- What was her name?
- Tobolovsky.
特巴洛斯基夫人
Mrs Tobolovsky.
很好
Nice lady.
收拾一下吧，清洁工
Clean up the mess, garbage man.
好了！她是你女儿，她也是美国公民
All right, she's your daughter
and she's an American citizen.
我不会打听你们的关系，这是你们的事
I ain't gonna ask what the deal is
with her. That's your business.
不过我想说的是，找关系是很困难的
But I'm gonna tell you,
pulling strings is hard work,
困难的工作一般不会免费
and hard work don't come free.
开个价吧，沃夫队长
Your price, Captain Wolf?
中国城辖区多交20%
Chinatown precinct take goes up 20%.
布朗克斯，布鲁克林每个月各涨10%
Bronx 121st, Brooklyn divisions,
each go up by 10%, monthly.
这个价格对于一个小女孩的护照和文书工作来说太过分了
That's a steep price for a passport
and some papers for a little girl.
现在的日子都不好过啊
Things are tough all over.
中国城加10%
Chinatown gets upped 10%.
布朗克斯和布鲁克林不变
Bronx and Brooklyn will settle
for the current rate
然后我们在感受到压力的时候
and the fact
that we won't start shooting
不会随意射杀街上的警察和警察家属
cops and their families in the streets
like dogs at the first sign of pressure.
现在的日子都不好过啊
Things are tough all over.
嘿，朋友，我见过你，我看过你在新泽西的拳击
Hey, man, I know you.
I saw yourfight in Jersey.
实在是太棒了，你轻松干掉了那家伙
It was really good.
You knocked that guy out.
- 不是的
- 我有好东西，兄弟
- No.
- That was some good shit, man.
很棒的格斗
Great fight.
赌场呢？
The casino?
80万整？
Exactly 800,000?
大约80万
It's almost 800.
我不是问你是不是大概80万
I'm not asking you if it's almost 800.
我要准确数字
I want the exact number.
78万5370美元
$785,370.
- 再上一周呢？
- 在亏钱
- And the week before?
- It's losing money.
- 怎么？
- 为什么？
- What?
- Why?
因为他损害了生意，生意是件很严肃的事情
Because he was hurting business,
and business is a serious matter.
我懂生意
I understand business.
但是既然要杀他，为什么还要打他？
But why beat him
if you were going to kill him anyway?
靠，靠！
Fuck you. Fuck you!
- 你不能进来
- 我只想要些吃的！
- You can't come in the shelter.
- Just trying to get something to eat!
赶紧睡觉！5分钟后熄灯
Wrap it up. Lights out in five.
赶紧睡觉
Wrap it up.
快点
Come on, guys.
好鞋子
Nice kicks.
最好早上它们还在，不然你就得用耳朵穿上它们了
They'd better be here in the morning
or you'll be wearing them on your ears,
因为我会把你的脚给扭下来
'cause I'll chew yourfeet off
at the goddamn ankles.
我真的想要双新点的鞋子，我会为你做任何事情
I could really use some new shoes, man.
I'll do whatever you want, you know?
任何能帮你熬过晚上的事情
Whatever gets you through the night.
- 我不能...
- 闭嘴，闭嘴！
- I just... I can't take another...
- Shut up. Shut up.
闭嘴，拿走吧，我还有旧鞋子
Shut up and take them.
I've still got my old ones.
好好照顾你的脚
Go and get those feet looked at.
都烂掉了
Gangrene's setting in.
我会的，谢谢你，朋友
I will. Thank you, man.
上帝保佑你，兄弟，上帝保佑你
Jesus loves you, brother.
Jesus loves you.
熄灯了，明早七点会叫醒你们的
Lights out. Wake-up call's 7am.
熄灯
Lights out.
嘘
Shh.
梅，我有个坏消息
Mei, I have sad news.
我听到他们在谈论…你妈妈走了
I heard them talking and...
your mother is gone.
她两周前在医院去世了
She died two weeks ago in the hospital.
他们不会告诉你的
They werert going to tell you,
但是我告诉你，这样子你可以为她的灵魂祈祷
but I'm telling you
so that you can pray
让她找到去天堂的路
for her soul to find its way to heaven.
别告诉他们，如果他们发现我告诉你…
Please don't say anything.
If they find out I told you...
我会保密的，谢谢
I won't say anything. Thank you
所有人起床！9点前离开这里
Everybody up.
Shelter needs to be cleared by 9am.
在3：30前办好今晚的床铺预定
Bed reservations for tonight
need to be made by 3:30.
带走所有个人物品
Please remove
all your personal belongings.
所有人起床！走了！
Everybody up. Come on, let's go.
带好个人物品，你们知道规矩的
Take your belongings with you.
You know the drill.
那么，告诉我们发生了什么
So you wanna tell us what happened?
有人喜欢那鞋子
Someone liked his shoes.
搞笑的家伙！你认为这是个玩笑？
Funny guy. You think this is a joke?
你们知道的，你们这帮保安有多糟糕
You know, you guys
are a hell of a crack security squad.
你做的很对，你本来可以说些什么的
You were right here.
You could have said something.
但是你喝醉酒忙着睡觉，是不是？
But you were too busy
sleeping off this contraband, right?
你如果再来这个避难所
Come into this shelter again
我就把你踹到大街上去
and I'm gonna run your raggedy ass
back out into the street.
嘿！走路不看路的？
Hey! Watch where you're going, man.
要不要给你点颜色瞧瞧？
You could get your ass
kicked for that, OK? Huh?
4块5毛5
4.55.
你没钱就得出去
If you got no money,
you gotta get out of line.
我有钱
I got money.
他没有钱，看看他那样子
He doesn't have any money.
Look at him.
先生，我告诉过你，如果你没钱，你得离开，懂吗？
Mister, I told you, if you don't
have money, you have to leave, OK?
让开，还有人在等呢
You gotta get out of line.
People are waiting.
走开，兄弟，让开
Come on, buddy. You gotta go.
- 这家伙惹麻烦了吗？
- 他疯了，长官
- This guy giving you trouble?
- He's crazy, Officer.
- 把他带出去，好吗？
- 好的，过来，我们走
- Get him out of here, OK?
- All right, come on, let's go.
嘿，你！过来，我们走！出去！到街上去！
Hey, you, come on. Let's go.
Out. On the street.
哥们，如果你想当小丑，去马戏团
Let's go, funny boy. You wanna be
a clown, go join the circus.
别在我辖区闹事，听懂了吗？
我不想在这附近再见到你，嘿！
Not in my precinct, you hear me?
I don't wanna see you around here. Hey.
上帝啊
Jesus Christ.
看看我抓到了谁
Look what the cat dragged in.
不可思议
Unbelievable.
- 看着他
- 看着他？
- Look at him.
- Look at him?
不去闻闻？
How about the smell?
我打电话叫大家过来
Think I'll call the boys.
想我们吗，伙计？
You miss us, partner?
欢迎回来
Welcome back to the force.
梅…
Mei...
对不起，我不能让他们抓到你
I'm sorry. I can't let them have you.
梅！回来这里！
Mei! Get back here!
- 日子过的怎么样，路克？
- 悲剧，不过正在变好
- How's your day been, Luke?
- Started lousy. But it's looking up.
路克・莱特，以前纽约最佳警察
Luke Wright, the Big Apple's hardest cop
once upon a time.
什么都敢试，但你知道你真正的才能吗？
You always could take a shot.
But you know what your real talent is?
你是个牵线人！我是说，谁会想到
You're a uniter. I mean, who'd
have thought that us and the Russkies
我们会和俄国佬拴在一起？
would ever be on the same page
about anything?
不是我！很高兴见到你，混蛋！
Not me. Nice to see you, rat.
自从你出卖我们，我就一直想这么做了
Been wanting to do this ever since the
day you opened your big fucking mouth!
当我们听说德切斯基如何对付你时，我笑惨了
When we heard what Docheski did to you,
I mean, I had to laugh.
对于安妮我们很抱歉
I mean, we felt bad for Annie ar all.
她知道她和谁在一起
Them's the breaks.
She knew who she was with.
街上有流言说你回来的时候
Word come up from the street
you were back,
我们甚至不敢相信
we couldn't believe our fucking ears.
你为什么回来？为什么不远走高飞？
Why would you come back? Why wouldn't
you disappear somewhere far way, huh?
比如说月球
Like the moon.
我想家了
I missed home.
你曾是我们一员，路克，我们曾是一个团队，一个家庭
You were one of us, Luke.
We were a team. We were family.
- 然后你扔下了我们
- 我们曾经有多风光，混蛋
- Then you threw us under the bus.
- We were kings, you son of a bitch!
现在，我们只是一群可怜虫
Now we're bunch of goddamn serfs.
嘿，嘿，冷静，伯努瓦
Hey, hey, easy, Benoit, huh?
当你回来的时候，我们以为你想寻死
When you came back,
we figured you wanted to die.
我们还开了个盘口赌你怎么死，你知道的
We got a pool going on when
you're gonna end it and how, you know,
公交，火车…
bus, train...
我赌“找警察自杀”
I got my money on suicide by cop.
来吧，拿好了
Come on, take it.
来一枪，来吧
Take a shot. Come on.
安妮在等着你
Annie's waiting for you.
问题是，你真的认为她想再见到你吗
Question is, do you really think
she wants to see you again?
嗯？
Hmm?
其实我真正的才能是让别人输钱
Actually, my real talent
is costing other people money.
你早就应该知道的，拉斯基
You ought to know that, Lesky.
你会输钱的，除非你朝我背后开枪
You're gonna lose that bet.
Unless you wanna shoot me in the back.
不过对你来说也不是第一次了
Wouldrt be your first time.
你为什么不了结这一切？
Why don't you just end it?
你在等什么？
What are you waiting for?
身边的人死去更多？
More people around you to die?
你到底在等什么？
What are you waiting for?
最后一次，告诉我那些数字
For the last time,
give me the numbers.
你是个勇敢的女孩，而且很聪明
You're a very brave girl, and clever.
但你知道我们如何知道你的本事吗？
But do you know how we knew exactly
what you can do,
你要在什么时间去什么地方
where you're going to be and when?
- 有人告诉你了
- 对
- Someone told you.
- That's right.
猜猜是谁？
Can you guess who?
你的朋友，告诉你关于你可怜母亲事情的人
Yourfriend, the one who told you
about your poor mother
将你从家里带走的流氓可不会告诉你那些
when the scum
who took you from home would not.
她在帮我们做事
She's working for us with a smile.
玲
Ling.
讲英语
In English.
我说了，讲英语！
I said speak in English.
怎么样？
Well?
她不肯告诉我任何事
She won't tell me anything.
我的父亲很有耐心
My father is a patient man.
我没有
I am not.
告诉他他想知道的一切
Tell him what he wants to know.
不然我就…
Or I'II...
纽约警察！开门！
NYPD! Open the door!
- 搞什么？
- 我们是警察
- What the hell?
- This is the police.
我们接到报警说扰民
We got reports of a disturbance.
你可以选择配合或者硬来
Look, you can make this easy
or you can make it hard.
开门，不然我们就要砸门了
Open the door or we come in by force.
放屁
Bullshit, blue.
你敢进来就别想活着出去，我以母亲之名发誓
You come in here, you go out feet first,
I swear on my mother.
他们在里面，队长
Yeah, they're in there, Captain.
他们一点都不配合，你最好在事情失控前过来
They're not cooperating. You better
get down here before things go to hell.
不行，这事闹大了
Negative, negative. This is big.
我马上回警局指挥，我们再联系
I'm going back to the station to monitor
the city. I'll get back to you.
好了，我们找到她了，你知道我想要什么
All right, we got 'em pinned down.
You know what I want.
我们有言在先，抓到女孩，可以就活捉，不行就干掉
We have a deal. Get the girl,
alive if you can, dead if you can't.
我们进去的话，布鲁克林上升10%，这是新的约定
We go in, Brooklyrs take
goes up by 10%. That's the new deal.
等等，我有个电话要接
Hold on, I got an incoming call.
- 嘿，埃米尔，怎么了？
- 把你的人弄走，混蛋
- Emile, what's up?
- Take your men off, Wolf.
不管中国人给你什么，我都加5%
Whatever the Chinese offered to you,
I'll up it by 5%.
把她带回来
Get her back here.
好了，关
All right, Quan,
俄罗斯人提供我布鲁克林7%
I got the Russians
offering to up Brooklyrs take by 7%,
布朗克斯也一样，所以我不知道该怎么和你说
Bronx the same.
So I don't know what to tell you.
我的手下，他们宁愿去打仗
My guys are willing
to go to war over this.
卡在我们和俄国人之间
You're gonna be stuck between us
and the Russians like Hitler,
就像希特勒双线作战，所以你要想清楚
fighting on two fronts,
so you better think hard about this one.
10%，两个区域，最终提案
10%, both precincts, final offer.
嘿，麦克，这两帮家伙都愿意
Hey, Mac. Both these bastards
are willing to pay a stiff price
为这小姑娘出大价钱
for this little Chink girl.
- 不管她有什么，我想要
- 那我们的计划是？
- Whatever she's got, I want it.
- So what's our play?
我让俄国人放下武器，你们进去
I get the Russians
to drop their guard, you go in.
如果她中枪了
She catches a bullet,
I want you to take out every last one
你给我把布尔什维克的都干掉
of those Bolshevik scumbags.
好的，埃米尔，你的提议不错
All right, Emile, your offer's good.
我会让我的人撤走的，只因为我更喜欢你！
I'm gonna call my guys off,
but only 'cause I like you better.
狗屁！你是个贪婪的混蛋，沃夫
Bullshit. You're a greedy bastard, Wolf.
你的嗅觉很灵敏，你想把一切占为己有
You got the scent of something big
and now you want it all for yourself.
不过我想在你派手下进来前告诉你些事情
But I have to tell you something before
you send your men in guns blazing.
- 她不见了
- 你指什么，她不见了？
- She's gone.
- What do you mean, she's gone?
她逃走了，你的人堵在外面我没法追她
I mean she escaped, and with
all your men out there, I can't follow.
我提议在找到她之前我们停战
I offeryou a truce until we find her.
我发誓，如果中国人先找到她
Trust me, the Chinese find her first,
你会为此后悔一辈子的
that will be a thing you regret
as long as you live.
德切斯基，她到底知道些什么？
Docheski, what does she have?
我们说定了吗，沃夫队长？
Do we have a truce, Captain Wolf?
女孩是中国人，11岁
The girl is Chinese, 11 years old.
会说普通话和英语
She speaks Mandarin and English.
照片已经下发
A photo is being disseminated.
找到她后直接带她去中心大街
You are to find her
and bring her straight to Centre Street.
她在往地铁去
She's heading for subway.
对不起，安妮
Sorry, Annie.
俄国人的手机信号在J大街消失了
Lost my lock
on the Russian cell on Jay Street.
听起来他们是进了地铁站
Sounds like they went into
the subway station. Manattan bound.
嘿
Hey.
你？那个清洁工？
You? The garbage collector?
你们的情报太糟糕了
You've got bad information.
我从来不收垃圾
我只丢垃圾
I never collected garbage.
I disposed of it.
别被吓得失眠了，他应得的
Don't lose sleep. He had it coming.
你还好吗？
Are you all right?
- 出去！出去！
- 快
- Get out! Get out!
- Move.
没事了
It's OK.
最后目击到女孩进了J大街地铁站，红色警报
Girl was last seen entering
Jay Street Station. Red alert.
一旦找到，立刻带她到中央大街的沃夫队长这
Once found, she needs to be brought
to Captain Wolf at Centre Street.
重复，红色警报
Repeat, red alert.
嘿，孩子，我们是警察
Whoa. Easy. Easy there, hon.
We're the police.
好了没事了
Everything's all right.
你叫什么？孩子
Hey, what's your name, hon?
就是她
This is her.
我不知道，对我来说他们看起来都一样
I don't know. They all look alike to me.
- 你有那照片吗？
- 有，让我看看…
- You got that picture up?
- Yeah, let me see.
该死的纽约
Fucking New York City.
好久没见到某些人的话
Don't see somebody for years.
你一天会遇到他们两次
Then you bump into them twice
in the same day.
我不会伤害你的，孩子
Hey, hey, hey. I'm not gonna hurt you.
你到底做了什么，孩子？
What the hell did you do, kid?
这些追你的都是坏人
You know, those men chasing you are bad.
你能告诉我他们为什么追你吗
You wanna tell me why they're after you?
你懂我在说什么吗？
You understand me?
你会说英语吗？
Speak English?
走另一边！都是车！
The other way! Cars go the other way!
你疯了吗？
Are you a crazy man?
坐稳了
Hold on.
这样下去,很多无辜的人会受伤
If this goes on, a lot of
innocent people are gonna get hurt.
你希望那样子吗?
You want that?
很好！那就按我说的做
Good. Then do what I say.
你还好吗？
You OK?
我们走
Let's go.
我不是5岁小孩
I'm not five years old.
那就跟上
Then keep up
- 你们找到后又跟丢了？
- 不，队长，我们没有跟丢她
- You had her and you lost her.
- No, Captain, we didn't lose her.
她被抢走了
She was taken by force.
- 俄国人？
- 不是俄国人
- The Russians?
- No, not the Russians.
好吧…
Well...
- 是路克・莱特
- 什么？
- It was Luke Wright.
- What?
- 沃夫队长
- 等会，大卫
- Captain Wolf?
- Not now, David.
市长想找你，队长
The mayor wants you, Captain.
- 把他接到2线
- 不是电话
- Put him through on two.
- He's not on the phone.
他想让你去大厦…昨天
He wants you at the mansion, yesterday.
给您
There you go.
- 谢谢，伊万诺夫先生
- 谢谢
- Thank you, Mr Ivanov.
- Thank you.
伊万诺夫先生？给您，伊万诺夫先生，1012号房间
Mr Ivanov?
Here you are, Mr Ivanov. Room 1012.
- 10楼
- 谢谢
- Tenth Floor.
- Thank you.
你喜欢高档酒店？
You like a nice hotel.
我从来没住过高档酒店
I've never stayed in a nice hotel.
所以没人会到这种地方找我们
No one's gonna look for us in one.
多想现在洗个澡啊
Would I love a shower right now.
你可以洗的
You could use one.
我大可以让俄国人把你带下列车
I could have just let those Russians
grab you on the train.
那你为什么要救我？
Why did you save me?
我没救你…是你救了我
I didn't save you. You saved me.
我只是作为回报
I'm paying you back.
我叫路克
My name's Luke.
梅
Mei.
你有父母吗，梅？
You have parents, Mei?
- 我有父亲
- 他叫什么?
- I have a father.
- What's his name?
张关
Chang Quan.
张关？
Chang Quan?
如果我们是在说同一个人的话
If we're talking about the same guy,
据我所知他根本没孩子
he didn't have any kids
last time I checked.
这没道理，他不可能有像你那么大的孩子
Any made since
wouldn't be a day over three years old.
我是领养的
I'm adopted.
他从老家带你来这的？
He bring you overfrom back home?
张不像是个做父亲的人
Chang isn't the fatherly type.
你为什么来这，梅？
Why are you here, Mei?
做会计
To count.
你是被张的老板，那个老家伙送来的？他叫什么？
You were sent over by the old guy,
Chang's boss. What's his name?
没有电脑，没有电子资料
Old school.
No computers, no electronic trails.
只有你脑子里的东西，是吗？
Just what you have
in your head, right?
- 你知道韩礁吗？
- 我知道他
- You know Jiao Han?
- I know of him.
他告诉了我一个数字，非常长的一个数字
He told me a number,
a very long number.
我本来要去个地方拿下个数字和指示
I was going someplace where I would get
another number and more instructions,
但是俄国人现身杀了所有人
but the Russian came and shot everyone.
之后警察又出现了，我就逃走了
Then the police came and I ran away.
现在你知道一切了，高兴了吗？
Now you know everything.
Happiness for you?
想回去找韩礁吗？
You wanna go back to Han Jiao?
我造成了太多麻烦
生意搞砸了
I make too much trouble. Bad business.
事成之后，他会杀掉我，真是如意算盘
After I do what he asks, he kills me.
Good business.
那么，这组数字是什么？
So what about this number?
一个又长又无聊的数字，我可以告诉你
It's a long, boring number.
I can tell it to you.
对我来说毫无意义
It wouldn't mean anything to me.
你怎么知道是一个数字而非一堆独立数字呢？
How do you know it's one number
and not a bunch of separate numbers?
你是个疯子，但是倒不蠢
You're a crazy man but not so stupid.
这些数字对你来说有何特别吗？
Is there anything interesting to you
about these numbers?
- 或许有点
- 为什么？
- Maybe a few of them.
- Why?
因为他们都是3或者7开头
Because they have a three or a seven
before them.
所有数字都是随机的
All the numbers are random,
但当中5个是7开头的，8个是3开头的
but five of them has a seven before
and eight of them has a three before.
对于随机数来说这频率太高
That's too many times to be random.
这是个密码
It's a code.
- 还有呢？
- 没了
- What else?
- Nothing.
那么，这些3和7是比较有用的
So the three and the seven
are interesting
因为他们随机出现了太多次？
because they happen too many times
to be random.
因为它们不是数字，是单词
Because they're not numbers.
They're words.
从左到右或者从右到左
Right left or left right.
老手法了，保险箱的密码
Old school. Combination to a safe.
在这个酒店里？
In the hotel?
哪？
Where?
大概5尺11寸，褐色头发，30岁左右
About five eleven, brown hair, 30s.
大概几小时前来的
Probably came in here
less than a few hours ago.
先生，我们不允许透露顾客信息
Sir, we're not allowed
to discuss our guests.
那么，他确实是客人了？他入住了吗？
So he's a guest? Did he check in?
对不起，先生，我们不能…
I'm sorry, sir.
We're not at liberty to...
他和一个中国女孩在一起，11岁
He would have been with a Chinese girl,
11 years old.
我是她的父亲，我很担心她
I'm herfather
and I'm very worried about her.
真抱歉，我可以帮你报警
I'm so sorry.
I can call the police for you.
你敢报警我杀了你
Do that and I blow your brains out.
- 现在…
- 别动
- Now...
- Don't move.
他在哪个房间？
...what room is he in?
哪个房间？
What room is he in?
我想…他是在10楼
I think maybe
I put him on the 10th floor.
哪个房间？
Room.
我发誓，他没有带着一个小女孩
I swear he didn't have
a little girl with him.
- 房间
- 我需要查一下
- Room.
- I just need to check.
那就快查，或者我给你一枪
Then check quick
or I put a bullet in your brain.
- 快
- 把手举起来
- Quick.
- Put your hands up.
- 你不会想这么做的
- 把手举高让我看见
- You don't want any part of this.
- Hands up so I can see 'em.
没人可以离开这酒店
No one leaves the hotel!
快点！
Come on!
1012，他在1012房
1012. He's in room 1012.
我以为你说没人会到这里找我们
I thought you said
no one would look for us here.
我把它关掉了，没人能打进来
I turned it off
so no one could call when I was...
它不需要被开着
It doesn't need to be on.
- 回去！
- 等等！
- Get back!
- Wait!
都给我趴在地上！
Get down on the floor.
所有人回去！
Everybody back!
写下那些数字
Write down the numbers,
那些3和7开头的，快！
just the ones with the three
and the seven in front of 'em, quick.
你！过来这里！趴下！趴下！
You, get over there! Get down! Get down!
我会想办法带你去安全的地方
I'll try to get you someplace safe.
如果我们分开了，别说你跟我说过什么！
We get separated,
don't tell them you told me anything.
- 梅，如果他们试图吓唬你…
- 试图？我已经被吓到了！
- Mei, if they try to scare you...
- Try? I'm so scared already.
嗯，我也是，记住，撒谎！
Yeah, me to. Remember, lie.
我们快到了
We're almost there.
如果你们看到他们下楼，小心别杀了那个女孩
If you see them downstairs,
try not to kill the girl.
进去
Back inside.
跟上他们！我下楼去断他们退路！
Follow them!
I'm going back down to cut them off.
警察来了，顶住他们直到我下令撤退！
The cops are here.
Hold them off until I give the word.
别让他们进来
Do not let them in!
所有人给我趴下，你们走不了了
Everybody stay down!
You ain't going nowhere! Stay!
嘿！你去哪？回去！站住！蹲下！都回去！
Hey, where you going?
Get down! No! Get back down!
- 回去！
- 快！快！
- Get back!
- Move! Move!
起来！所有人起来！
Get up! Everybody up!
我们要离开酒店了，起来！
We're getting out of the hotel. Up!
站起来，不然我就开枪了！站起来！
Up or I start shooting you! Up!
58号转角，我们发现嫌疑犯
Moving to corner of 58.
We got a suspect.
别动！
Hey, don't move!
Don't move!
走！往那走！
Move! Move! Over there! Go!
到街上去，别停！谁不听话下场就是这样！
Into the street and keep moving!
Anyone who doesn't dies like this!
到街上去
Into the street!
重复，别开枪！
Repeat, hold your fire!
那些都是平民！
They're civilians!
嫌犯在人群中，嫌犯在人群中
Suspect is in the crowd.
嘿！给我站住！
Hey, stop right there!
嘿，你干什么！
Hey! What the hell are you doing?
我的车！做点什么！他抢了我的车！
That's my car!
Do something, he took my fucking car!
往市中心开，我过一会告诉你地址
Head downtown.
I'll give you an address in a minute.
靠
Shit.
- 嘿，朋友！可以告诉我地址了吗？
- 等一下
- Hey, buddy, you wanna give me address?
- In a minute. Just hold on.
他回来了？路克・莱特回到我的城市了？
He's here? Luke Wright is back
in the city, in my city?
他已经回来有一段时间了
He's been back for a while.
- 一段时间？多久？
- 可能一年，这很难说
- A while? What's a while?
- Maybe a year. It's hard to say.
挂掉电话！
Turn that goddamn thing off.
- 亚历克斯
- 朋友们
- Alex.
- Guys.
是，对不起，市长
Yes, sir. Sorry, Your Honour.
发生了什么，沃夫？路克・莱特又是怎么卷进来的？
What's going on, Wolf?
And how's Luke Wright involved in it?
我本来也想问你这个问题
I figured I might ask you
the same question.
别和我玩游戏
Don't try to game me.
你不过就是个马前卒
You're nothing but a pawn
下着一盘你无法掌控的大棋
playing on a board so big
you can't even see the edge.
仅此而已
That's all you've ever been.
直到5分钟前我都比你更了解路克・莱特
I knew about Luke Wright, which is more
than you can say until five minutes ago.
你所知的路克・莱特
What you know about Luke Wright
还不到浩瀚资料中的一小片段
rates less than a paragraph
in a very fat book.
世贸大厦倒下后
After the towers fell
我们的人都分散出去追寻恐怖活动
and our manpower was spread out
tracking terrorist activity,
是我组织了特勤队
I was the one
who formed the special task force
惩治犯罪以填补缺口
to deal with the crime
that was filling the gap.
别忘了也是我让你来管理这支队伍
And don't you ever fucking forget that
I was the one who put you in charge.
我从来没忘记…我的工作成就了你的市长
I didn't forget. My work made you mayor.
你的工作？
Your work?
你以为路克只是你警察中的一员？
You think Luke
was just one of your cops?
当我拉起队伍时，我知道它需要一面刀锋
When I put together your team,
I knew it needed an edge
普通警探无法胜任，得像手术刀刀锋一般
no ordinary detectives could give me,
something surgical.
我拜托那些甚至不存在于官方记录中的朋友
I called friends in places buried
so deep they don't officially exist.
他们很同情我，一周后他们送来了路克・莱特
They were sympathetic.
A week later they sent Luke Wright.
那些过去七年里消失的自作聪明的家伙
Those wise guys who vanished
over the last seven years,
你以为他们死于自相残杀？
you think that was internecine war?
你在哈林区排水沟里找到的可卡因
Those coke kings
you found in the gutter in Harlem.
布鲁克林的弗雷迪・彼得罗维奇，中国城的汤米・劳
Freddy Petrovich in Brooklyn.
Tommy Lau in Chinatown.
路克・莱特是个幽灵
Luke Wright is a ghost.
非常致命的幽灵
A very deadly ghost.
而且工作很效率
It worked like a charm too.
然后你们这帮混蛋就忙着捞钱了
Then you dicks had to get greedy
and pad your pockets.
路克是个杀手，但是个诚实的杀手
Luke's a killer, but he's an honest one.
当他威胁说要把向情报局告发一切时
When he threatened to take
the whole thing to IA,
当时确实费了很大的劲
it took some people with a lot of bronze
stuck to their pyjamas
才搞定他
to talk him off the ledge.
如果我的队伍解散，我们就又变回苦力了
Yeah, my team gets dismantled.
We're peons again.
但是如果路克・莱特有这么深背景
But if Luke Wright's so connected,
为什么他会沦落到在泽西打拳击
how does he wind up in Jersey
cage fighting on the B circuit?
我看起来像心理医生吗？
Do I look like a shrink?
动员起所有人来
Get everybody on this.
一旦路克・莱特有了目标
Once Luke Wright gets on a roll,
整个城市只有一个人能在
一对一中和他抗衡
only one man in this city
can take him on one-on-one.
打扰了,我知道我不该打扰你们
I know this is a closed door,
但是市中心一座酒店发生了大规模枪战
but there was just a major gun battle
downtown at a hotel.
媒体都疯了,您需要赶紧做一份声明
Media's going nuts.
You're gonna need to make a statement.
韩礁现在也在城里
Han Jiao is in the city also.
他给了那个中国女孩一些东西,我不知道的东西
He give this little Chinese girl
something, I don't know what.
路克・莱特在我之前带走了她
Luke Wright grabbed her before I could.
- 什么？
- 我说路克・莱特
- What?
- I said Luke Wright...
知道了，我一开始就听到了
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
I heard you the first time.
关闭曼哈顿的每一个出口
Close every exit out of Manattan.
确保莱特和那个女孩逃不出去
Make sure that neither Wright or the
girl gets away, you get commissioner.
放跑了...你就找把铲子自掘坟墓吧
Let 'em go... you get a shovel
to dig your own grave.
那个女孩绝不能离开这个城市
That girl does not leave this city.
我们找到了女孩，但是信息可能已经被泄漏
We recovered the girl, but the
information might have been compromised.
- 我们要改下时间表吗？
- 不可能
- Should we change our time frame?
- lmpossible.
现在整件事情已经失控了
Now that the whole damn thing
has gone supernova,
今晚一定要了结此事
it's going to happen
and it's gonna happen tonight.
会面地点要改下
But the meeting place
needs to be changed.
- 到哪？
- 我会告诉你的
- Where to?
- I'll let you know.
这里！就这里！
Here. Right here.
慢点，停车
Slow down. Stop the car.
不行，不行，别把妓女带上我的车子
No, no, you don't bring
no hookers in my cab, man.
继续打你的表
Just keep the meter running.
小姐们
Ladies.
去喝一杯如何？
How about a drink?
晚上好
Good evening.
- 晚上好
- 想在这里吃晚餐吗？
- Evening.
- Will you be joining us for dinner?
- 我们没有预定
- 没事的
- We don't have a reservation.
- That's OK.
今晚虽然很忙，但是我们应该能给你们找到位置
We're busy tonight, but we should
be able to find you something.
楼下已经没有空位了，不过背后还有些
We don't have any tables downstairs,
but there are some in the back.
或者如果你们喜欢的话，去楼上也可以
Or you could sit upstairs if you like.
先生？您怎么看？先生？
Sir? Sir?
Do you have a preference? Sir?
我们就在吧台喝点酒
I think we'll just get a drink
at the bar.
你亲我一下然后转身出去
I want you to give me a kiss,
turn round and walk out of here.
- 但是我以为
- 就像你忘记了什么东西一样
- But I thought...
- Just act like you forgot something.
只是不要再回来了
Only don't come back.
来杯白俄罗斯，还有把叉子
Give me a white Russian, please,
and a fork.
- 叉子？
- 就那样的
- Fork?
- One of those.
他开的什么车？停在哪？
What does he drive
and where is it parked?
外面小路上的一辆银色的SUV
A silver SUV in the alley outside.
- 瓦西里
- 打错了
- Vassily.
- Not even close.
你是谁？
Who is this?
整晚都在屠戮你手下的人，埃米尔
The guy who's been
killing your boys all night, Emile.
你的儿子在我手里
The guy who has your son tied up
in a very dark place.
听好，我想要…
Now, here's what I want.
你以为我会关心你想要什么？
You think I give a shit
of what you want?
你以为抓了瓦西里就能敲诈我？
Do you think you can blackmail me
because you have Vassily?
- 杀了他，下地狱去吧
- 我会下地狱的
- Kill him and go to hell.
- I'm going to hell all right.
不过我不会杀了你儿子
But I'm not gonna kill your boy.
我会把他带在身边，就像宠物一样
I'm gonna keep him around, like a pet.
我对待宠物可不友善
A very badly treated pet.
我会做一些让我以后每次照镜子
I'm gonna do things to him
that'll make me ashamed
都觉得屈辱的事情，但是我会这么做的
to look in the mirror afterward,
but I will do them.
瓦西里会告诉我所有他所知道的
Vassily's gonna tell me everything
he knows about your operation.
然后你准备怎么做？报警？
And then what you gonna do?
Tell the police?
- 你在搞笑吗？
- 我之前有提到过警察吗？
- You want me to laugh?
- Who said anything about the police?
我会把这些信息与你的竞争对手分享
I'm gonna share the information
with the competition,
我还没干掉的那些家伙
the ones I haven't already killed.
我会拿光你所有的东西
Anything they don't take from you,
I will.
首先我会带走你漂亮的老婆
First I'm gonna take your trophy wife.
然后是你的孩子们
Then I'm gonna take
your trophy children.
我会让你一无所有
I'm gonna leave you with nothing.
当我完事后，你就什么都不是了
When I'm done, you won't even be
a memory of a memory.
- 不过这些都没必要发生
- 你想要什么？
- But that doesn't have to happen.
- What do you want?
- 我想知道保险箱里有什么
- 什么保险箱？
- I wanna know what's in the safe.
- What safe?
那个女孩给我密码的那个保险箱
The safe the girl gave me
the combination to. That safe.
三千万美元
$30 million.
那孩子本来要去拿第二个密码，第二个保险箱里有什么？
Kid was on her way to get a second
number. What's in the second safe?
值三千万美元的东西
Something won'th $30 million.
- 给谁？
- 不知道
- To who?
- No idea.
那是因为你只有小聪明，埃米尔
That's 'cause
you're only half-smart, Emile.
那么，我们这么说定了…
So here's the deal.
你告诉我第一个保险箱在哪，我拿了钱就放你儿子
You tell me where the first safe is,
I take the money and let your boy go.
骗我的话你就死定了，说到做到
Lie to me and yourworld ends.
You have my word on that.
白痴！我知道一个人是否独行
Idiot. I know
when a man is working alone
而你正好只身一人
and you're as alone as one can be.
你需要一支队伍才能靠近保险箱
You need a small army
to get near that safe,
我有这种队伍
the kind of army I have.
曾经有过！我时间不多
Had. It's been shrinking by the minute.
最后一次机会，否则我就挂电话修理你儿子了
Last chance before I hang up
and go to work on your son.
你要杀我吗，收垃圾的？
Going to kill me, garbage man?
你那天就可以把我们都干掉的，是吗？
You could have taken us out that day,
couldn't you?
但是你只是跪在那里
But you just sat there,
让我们毁掉你，让你变得一无是处
let us ruin you,
let us make you nothing.
我猜是保险箱给了你新的动力，是吗，收垃圾的？
I guess finding out about that safe gave
you new motivation, eh garbage man?
如果我是你就不会浪费口舌
I wouldn't spend my time talking
if I were you.
会祈祷事情结束时，那小女孩还活着
Spend it praying that when this is over
that little girl's still alive.
祈祷！
Pray.
时间地点？
When and where?
桥下的地下道，一小时后
The underpass under the bridge,
one hour.
对不起，那些俄国人出现时我用枪指着你
I'm sorry I pointed a gun at you
when the Russians attacked us, Mei.
- 那只是…
- 生意而已…我知道的
- It was...
- Business. I know.
很好，很好，你理解
It's good. It's good you understand.
我们会搞定这一切
We're going to get this done
然后你跟我和韩叔一起就安全了
and you'll be safe
with me and Uncle Han.
我保证做一个好父亲
I promise to be a better father to you
比那个抛弃你和你母亲的家伙更好
than the one
who left you and your mother.
这个世界上没人比我更关心你
There's no one in the world
who cares more about you.
你知道的，是吗？
You know that, don't you?
人都到了
Well, the gang's all here.
差不多
Almost.
- 伯尼生病了？
- 他在医院，混蛋！
- Reddick have to call in sick?
- He's in the hospital, dickhead.
- 你打坏了他的气管
- 我从来不知道气管还能被打坏
- You broke his trachea.
- I didn't know a trachea could break.
- 希望他们能修好
- 是吗！不如让我先修理你？
- Hope they can fix it.
- Yeah? How about I fix you?
嘿！嘿！嘿！嘿！别这样！
Hey, hey, hey, hey. Not here.
好久不见，路克，不过我并不想念你
It's been a while, Luke.
Can't say I missed you.
- 那么，有话直说吧
- 带了我要的东西没？
- So, let's get down to business.
- Did you bring what I asked for?
- 托斯卡尼的
- 还有呢？
- Toscanni's.
- Where else?
味道不错！
Mmm. That's good.
我整晚都在餐馆里
Been in restaurants all night.
但是他们提供给我的都是子弹
All I got served was lead.
- 有火吗？
- 去你的！
- Anyone got a light?
- You know what? Screw this.
听着，队长，你让我们过来，我们过来了
Look, Captain, you asked us
to come here, so we came.
但我不会站在这里听这混蛋胡扯
But I ain't gonna sit here
and listen to this scumbag's big mouth.
闭嘴，科夫克斯！
Shut up, Kolfax.
还没戒烟，哈？
Still haven't quit, huh?
嘿，嘿，这是什么？
Hey. Hey, what the hell is that?
装有三千万美元保险箱的密码
Combination of the safe
with 30 million bucks in it.
- 哇，哇！你在干嘛？
- 你个狗屎
- Whoa, whoa, whoa.
- Filthy piece of shit.
现在这密码存在我脑子里了
The only place it exists now is in here.
当你们手痒想扣扳机时，记住这点
Remember that next time
your little triggerfinger gets itchy.
为什么韩礁会把它藏在
Why would Han Jiou stash it
中国城最繁忙的赌窝里？
right in the middle of Chinatowrs
busiest gambling den?
因为伯努瓦这样的喜欢
Because of sleaze-bucket cops
like you, Benoit,
去赌窝收保护费腐败警察
who collect off of Chinatowrs
busiest gambling den.
想不吸引警察的注意
Where else would he surround it
with dozens of armed man
他还能放在哪里？
without attracting police attention?
队长,我们怎么知道这混蛋不是在玩我们？他是个流浪汉！
Captain, why do we know this son of
a bitch on the level, huh? He's a bum.
你从哪得到的消息？
Where'd you get your information?
今晚会有个交易
There's an exchange happening tonight.
三合会半数交易额都在赌场保险箱里
The Triad half of the deal
is in a safe in the casino.
我一人搞不定，所以我叫了你们，老朋友们
No way I could get to it on my own,
so I called on you, my old pals.
三千万美元分六份依然是很大一笔钱
30 million split six ways
is still a lot of money.
我们风险太大，队长，尤其是你
We're risking a lot, Captain.
You especially.
所有人都知道你前途光明
Everybody knows you got a bright future.
谁保证的？你的市长？
Promised by who? His Honour?
他跟你承诺什么了，沃夫？
What carrot
is he teasing you with, Wolf?
若他知道你所掌握的，他还会放过你？
He's gonna let you out in the street
knowing what you know now?
你什么意思？
What's that supposed to mean?
意思是，他的第二任期快到头了，什么保证都是屁
His second term is gonna come to an end
and his hold on the city goes poof.
就跟普通公民一样
Just like that he's Joe Citizen again.
三千万是一笔不错的退休金
30 million would be
a nice retirement package.
他给中国佬什么好处？
What's he giving the Chinks?
如果我知道，还会跟你们这帮混蛋站在这里？
If I knew that, I wouldn't be standing
here with you assholes, would I?
光明未来，哈？
A bright future, huh?
头条
Big headlines.
“英雄警察破获纽约最大的地下赌博巢穴”
"Hero cops take down New York City's
biggest underground gambling operation."
每人五百万美元，且没人知道
Five million bucks apiece
that no one will ever know about,
就当是额外甜头
just to give it that extra sweet taste.
好了，谁进去过？拜托，谁进去过？
All right, who's been in there?
For Christ's sake, who's been in there?
- 我，队长
- 你俩做先锋
- Me, Cap.
- You two, you're on point.
里面都是平民，看准了打
Place is packed with civilians,
so exercise some judgement.
记住只有我有密码
Remember, I got the combination.
如果你们想要钱，掩护好我
You want that money, watch my back.
你要去哪？
Where are you going?
别动！待着！
Don't move! Stay!
让开！走！
Out of the way! Move!
嘿，你，去死吧！
Hey, you, settle down!
这里！走！
This way. Let's go.
小心
Heads up.
走
Go.
科夫克斯，干掉他
Kolfax, take him out.
掩护他
Cover him.
打开它，开枪！
Open it. Take it!
靠！
Oh, shit!
靠！我必须离开这里
Oh, shit.
I gotta get out of here.
操，操，队长
Oh, fuck. Fuck, Captain.
天啊，你个混蛋！你杀了同伴，你个混蛋！
God, you shit!
Shoot a man in the back, son of a bitch!
- 好了，米尔斯，我们往哪走？
- 这里
- All right, Mears, where we going?
- This way.
快
Move.
- 天堂之门到了
- 把我们这样的罪人拒之门外
- The gates of paradise.
- Locked and bolted to sinners like us.
好了，别浪费时间
Yeah, well,
let's not wait for an invitation.
好了，你个混蛋，快点开始
All right, you bastard. Get started.
下面按我说的做
Here's how we do this.
你们先放下枪，我再开保险箱
You put down your guns, I open the safe.
如果你们想杀我，随意
If you wanna shoot me, go ahead.
快点决定，真警察马上就要到了
Make your minds up quick
'cause the real cops'll be here soon.
放到地上
On the floor.
快点，你个混蛋，你想干什么？
Come on, you son of a bitch.
What are you trying to pull?
密码左右方向反了，马上就开了
I had right left switched.
It's gonna open.
你会活着的
You'll live.
左26
Left 26.
沃夫队长，这里发生了什么？
Captain Wolf,
what the hell happened in here?
你以为发生了什么，哈？我们突袭了这里
What do you think happened, huh?
We had a raid on the place go bad.
有人员伤亡，赶紧给我进去处理
We got dead cops, casualties.
Get in there, will you?
- 沃夫队长，你需要救护车
- 我需要一排救护车
- Captain Wolf, you need an ambulance.
- I need a fleet of ambulances.
赶紧叫救护车，懂吗？我自己开去医院
Call it in, will you? I'll take
my own busted ass to the hospital.
演技不错
Not bad.
如果你不是个两面派，我几乎都喜欢上你了
If you werert such a double-dealing
asshole, I could almost like you.
是几乎！开车！
Almost. Drive.
只是划伤
It's a scratch.
我不会杀你，但我可没说让你住大酒店
I'm not gonna kill you, but I didn't say
I was putting you up at the Ritz.
沃夫
Wolf.
我需要钱，丹尼
I have your money, Danny.
什么？
What?
你听见了
You heard me.
三千万！五千份一千美元的支票
30 million. Five-thousand
and one-thousand dollar bills.
- 我想谈谈
- 不行
- I wanna talk.
- No.
你需要的是冷静下来我们好谈点正常的
No, what you wanna do is calm down
so we can talk like adults.
闭嘴，丹尼
Shut it, Danny.
我是想谈，不过不是和你谈
I wanna talk,
but I don't wanna talk to you.
我要和你男朋友谈
I wanna talk to your boyfriend.
我是亚历克斯
This is Alex.
好久不见，亚历克斯
Been a while, Alex.
- 你怎么拿到这号码的？
- 别这样，亚历克斯
- How'd you get this number?
- Come on, Alex.
顺着市长的味就能找到你
Reach up the mayor's ass, there you are.
男人就该有男人样，哈？
A mars gotta do
what a mars gotta do, huh?
他总比安妮这诱饵好
He's a better catch
than Annie was anyway.
我一直不解你为什么会勾搭上那样一头奶牛
I never understood
how you hooked up with a cow like that.
绝不是因为她的长相，而是她的幽默感
It was never about her looks.
It was her sense of humour.
她现在没那么搞笑了，不是么？
She's not so funny now, is she?
不是了，我也一样
No, she's not. Neither am I.
我拿到了钱，亚历克斯，我杀了很多人才弄到的
I have the money, Alex.
I had to kill a lot of people to get it.
所以听着
So listen up.
你还没交换过密码，另一个保险箱里是什么？
You haven't made the combination
exchange yet. What's in the other safe?
一张碟片
A disc.
名字，钱的来龙去脉…
Names, money trails.
当指挥官派我们帮丹尼清理城市时
When our commanders sent the two of us
to help Danny clean up the city,
他们附加了一个条件
they attached a price.
作为交换，丹尼要自寻财路
In exchange, Danny looked the other way
而每笔被当做恐怖组织查抄的集团资金
while the assets seized from every group
deemed a terrorist organisation
则装进了他们的私人腰包
were funnelled
into their private accounts.
惊讶是他们受惊需要保护时
Amazing what people
let you get away with
却把你赶走了
when they're scared
and wanna feel protected.
惊讶的是有那么多小人
Amazing how many scumbags
there are out there
都等着乘机牟利
waiting to take advantage of it.
- 难道你没有么？
- 我退出了
- Like you didn't?
- I quit.
你以为这能帮那些被你私自送去见上帝的人
Bet that helps all those souls you sent
to meet their maker without due process
省下很多功夫吗？
rest a whole lot easier.
你以为你在拳击场上
You thought you could atone
by climbing into a cage
被人随意殴打就能赎罪吗？
and allowing yourself
to get beaten to a pulp?
别给我说教了，路克！
Don't fucking preach at me, Luke.
我只是收钱办事
I'm getting paid for services rendered.
是啊，你把碟片卖给中国人好让他们勒索我们上司
Right. You sell the disc to the Chinese
so they can blackmail our old honchos,
然后拿着三千万美元和丹尼去巴哈马别墅逍遥自在
take the 30 mill and waltz off
with Danny to a villa in the Bahamas.
是巴厘岛，不过无所谓了，不是么？
Bali, but whatever, right?
那么，就算你知道了，又如何？
So, now you know. Now what?
现在你要应付我
Now you're dealing with me.
- 好吧，我退出
- 不行
- All right, I'm turning around.
- No, you're not.
你说什么？你已经拿到钱了
What are you talking about?
You've got the money.
- 中国人手里没有我要的了
- 不，他们有我想要的
- The Chinese have nothing I care about.
- No. They have something I do.
把你保险箱密码给这女孩，她会给你我们的
Give the girl the combination to your
safe and she will give you our number.
我们到你的地方，你去我们的
We go to your location, you go to ours.
当我们拿到碟片，我们会给你解密密码
When we've gotten the disc,
we will explain the code
你拿到你的钱
and you'll get the cash.
一言为定
That's the deal.
- 说说看吧
- 这是个很长的数字
- Let's hear it.
- It's a very long number.
你最好能记下来
You'll want to write it down.
感谢上帝我还带了笔，哈？
Thank goodness I brought a pen, huh?
你最好闭上眼睛
You might wanna close your eyes.
随你便吧
Have it your way.
快接，路克
Come on, Luke.
老地方，就你和我
The old place, just you and me.
你是路克的朋友吗？
You're a friend of Luke?
这不是你该关心的
Not as far as you're concerned.
今晚席卷整个纽约的暴力活动
The violence
that has rocked the city tonight
依旧持续，不到一小时前
continued in a bloody gun battle
中国城一家夜总会爆发了血腥枪战
in a Chinatown nightclub
less than an hourago.
- 这已经完全失控了
- 你以为呢？
- This is really getting out of hand.
- You think?
谢谢提醒
Thanks for that insight.
市长，亚历克斯・罗瑟斯在你私人专线上
Your Honour,
Alex Rosers on your private line.
他说有急事
He says that it's urgent.
- 打扰一下，市长
- 我5分钟后回来，现在别烦我
- Excuse me, Your Honour.
- Back in five. Don't bother me now.
他为什么不打我手机？
Why didn't he call me on my cellphone?
我记得让你把所有电话都接到我的…
I thought I told you to put
all my calls through to the...
我一直跟你说这里保安水平太差
I always told you this place
had lousy security standards.
那是因为没人会疯到像你一样来这杀人
Because nobody's been crazy enough to
come in here and pull a stunt like this.
- 你有种，路克
- 是啊，真是惊讶我还能走路
- You got some balls, Luke.
- Yeah, amazing I can even walk.
给我碟片
The disc.
什么？你以为我会傻到让中国帮派
What, you think I'm stupid enough
to let a gang of Chinese
穿过前门进到房间来拿它？
walk up the front steps and collect it
from me in my living room?
- 它在离这很远的保险箱里
- 我不认为你很蠢
- It's in a safe far away from here.
- I don't think you're stupid.
所以我不认为你只有一份拷贝
Which is why I don't for a second
believe you gave away the only copy.
我会去见亚历克斯
I'm going to meet Alex.
你先给我碟片，不然我就在非要害的部位给你一枪
First you give me the disc or I'll put
bullets in places that won't kill you
让你下半辈子生不如死
but make you spend
the rest of your life wishing I had.
满意了?
Satisfied?
我要确认一下这不是“金刚葫芦娃”
I wanna make sure
it's not ABBA'sGreatest Hits.
亚历克斯会杀了你的,你知道的
Alex will kill you, you know.
嗯，或许吧
Yeah, probably.
上帝，路克，你气色很不好
Jesus. Luke, you look like hell.
酒精而已，缺少睡眠和阳光
Just alcohol, lack of sunlight,
sleep deprivation.
除此以外，我感觉不错
Other than that, I feel great.
呵，我在想，我们在这里抛过多少尸了？
You know, I was thinking, how many
bodies have we dumped in this place?
你知道的，我从不记数
You know, I didn't keep count.
他们都是混蛋，不是么？
They were all assholes, though, right?
放开她，亚历克斯
Let her go, Alex.
丹尼打电话说你去拜访过他
Danny called.
He told me about your visit.
我不得不承认，我都没想到这一手
I have to admit,
even I didn't see that one coming.
你现在有了钱和碟片
You had the disc and the money.
什么...
What...
她对你来说意味着什么？
What is she to you?
生命
Life.
好吧，趁还有命就好好享受吧
Well, enjoy it while it lasts,
不久她就会让你的小命玩完的
'cause she's the reason
yours is gonna be a whole lot shorter.
钱在哪，路克
The money, Luke.
在车里
In the car.
或者银行里
Or in the bank.
或者在中央车站储物柜里
Or in a series of lockers
at Grand Central.
或者我可能出于好心悉数捐出了
Or maybe I donated it to charity,
out of the goodness of my heart.
想要知道下落，你就得来硬的
You wanna find out where that money is,
you're gonna have to do it the hard way.
你还好吧，梅？
You all right, Mei?
我见过他打斗，你打不过他的
I saw him fight before.
Bad business for you.
是啊，最糟的是
Yeah. The worst.
你又救了我
You saved me, again.
我们救了对方
We save each other.
我知道你在想什么
I know how you feel.
帮我把这垃圾弄出来
Help me get this sack of garbage
out of the car.
确保他安全回到他老爸那儿
Make sure he gets to his daddy
safe and sound.
5万，赔偿你的损失
50 grand, for your trouble.
钱可能不多，但至少你有命花
Might not seem like much, but at least
you're gonna live to enjoy it.
在经历了这么多后，你还想放过他？
You want him safe and sound
after what he did to you?
为了她
For her sake.
若再见面，你就万事皆休
We meet again, all bets are off.
- 你妈的给我看路，哥们！
- 走你的
- Watch where you're fucking going, man!
- Keep walking.
- 什么？再说一遍？啥？
- 走开
- Excuse me? Pardon me? Anything?
- Walk.
这是他妈的纽约！
This is fucking New York City!
- 第五家银行了，还有几家？
- 没了
- Bank number five. How many more?
- That's it.
现在碟片拷贝已遍布城市保险柜
Got copies of the disc
in security boxes all over the city.
如果我们出事
Anything happens to us,
很多大人物就得倒霉
a lot of important people
are gonna be very sorry.
我们的护身符，这是笔好生意
Our security. Good business for us.
- 现在干嘛？
- 我们离开这里
- What now?
- Now we get out of town.
梅，你是个孩子…我不确定自己能否做个好父亲
Mei, you're a kid and...
I'm not sure I could be a good father.
我想我能力不足
I think that ship has sailed.
我不想要父亲
I don't want no more fathers.
你可以做我朋友吗？
Will you be my friend?
至死都愿
Till my dying day.
我找到一家在西雅图专门培训天才儿童的学校
I got info on a school
for gifted kids up in Seattle.
这会是次美妙旅行，如果你喜欢那里的风光的话
It's a nice drive,
if you like trees and shit.
我们安全了吗？
Are we safe?
别想太多，梅，别想太多
One day at a time, Mei.
One day at a time.